Ely Samuel Parker Papers 1794-1946 Mss.497.3.P223
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1794-1946; 1.5 linear feet
  - ALS to N. H. Parker, 1863 Nov. 18; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 5)
    A letter from Chattanooga, with instructions about the division of his property should he be killed in the war. Ely writes before a battle between Grant and Bragg, and refers to his duties on the staffs of Generals J.E. Smith, Wm. F. Smith, and U.S. Grant.
  - ALS to Caroline Parker, 1863 Nov. 21; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 5)
    Ely acknowledges Carrie's letter advising of William Parker's gradual recovery. He describes the country where his camp is located and the living standards of the people who occupy it.
  - AL to Caroline Parker, 1863 Dec. 2; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 5)
    Part of a letter describing a battle fought Nov. 23 to 28, during which Lt. Towner of Batavia was wounded.
  - ALS to N. H. Parker, 1864 Jan. 25; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 5)
    Ely discusses his transfer in September from Gen. J.E. Smith's Division to Grant's staff, his own serious illness which has resulted in a loss of thirty pounds, a five day battle at Chattanooga, etc.
  - Map of New Berne, N.C., 1864 Feb. 1; Parker, I. Newton (Box 5)
    Images note: A hand drawn map of the area around New Berne, with notations on verso concerning local place names and an encounter with the enemy on Feb. 1st to 3rd.
  - ALS to Martha [Parker], 1864 Apr. 1; Parker, I. Newton (Box 5)
    Newton describes what happens to Union soldiers who are captured by the Rebels "either with a whole skin or in a wounded state." He closes by admitting he is not an "apt person to write an interesting...sensible letter."
  - ALS to Nicholson H. Parker, 1864 Apr. 27; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 5)
    Note advising he has received telegram about Father's death, but could not reach home in time for funeral; written on verso of printed announcement of officers composing Grant's staff in the field.
  - [Buffalo?] Newspaper, 1864 [May?] (Box 5)
    William Parker's obituary.
  - ALS to [Caroline Parker?], 1864 June 26; Parker, Newton I. (Box 5)
    Newton asks for some mocassins as "our heavy government shoes are unbearable" in hot weather, also some summer socks and handkerchiefs. He would like to have two pudding sticks and two ladels as gifts for "two good families" who have been kind to him by relieving the monotony of army food. He closes by admitting he is not in a position "to make preemptory demands on our family resources, being, as you have intimated to me, of limited character."
  - Buffalo Express, 1864 [June?] (Box 5)
    Images note A group photograph of Grant and his staff, including Ely S. Parker, from the rotogravure section of the issue for May 30, 1920.
    - Brigadier General Ely S. Parker, 1863 [June?]
  - ALS to N. H. Parker, 1864 Oct. 24; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 5)
    A letter deploring the lack of unity among the Indians. Ely blames Dr. Wilson for the rupture with Washington, resulting from the Indians' behavior during a visit from [Acting? Commissioner Mix. He advises Nic against having anything to do with a proposed delegation to Washington, pointing out that the country is bankrupt.
  - ALS to N. H. Parker, 1864 Nov. 19; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 5)
    Brief letter giving highlights of a long talk with Commissioner Dole. The latter will not recognize the Chief government at Cattaraugus, is willing to treat with the New York Indians for their Kansas claims, and believes Rich is the strongest man for the New York agency.
  - ALS to Nicholson H. Parker, 1866 Nov. 21; Cunningham, H. S. (Box 5)
    Letter from the New York Indian Agent stating that he has just received his commission and that he will be pleased to retain Nic as interpreter.
  - Parker, Ely S., [1867] (Box 5)
    Images note: Photograph at the time of his marriage. [cf. Parker, A.C. The life of General Ely S. Parker... Buffalo, 1919, p. 146]
    - Brigadier General Ely S. Parker, [1867]
  - ALS to N. H. Parker, 1868 Mar. 25; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 5)
    A request to be kept informed about any rumors at home connected with possible changes in the New York Indian Agency.
  - ALS to Fred, Frank, Albert and Minnie Parker, 1868 Oct. 1; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 5)
    A reply from Army Headquarters, Washington, to letters from Nic's children. Ely tells them about his work for General Grant, who will oppose Seymour in the presidential elections, and speaks of Grant's four children. He and Aunt Minnie expect to go north in two or three weeks.
  - Plan of operation, 1868 ?; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 5)
    A "plan of operation" dealing with the advisability of waiting until the matter of title to the Indian lands has been settled by the New York Courts, before reviving in Washington the question of abrogation of the treaties.
  - ALS to N. H. Parker, 1869 May 25; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 5)
    A letter commenting briefly on the Tonawanda census and advising that Sherman will be superseded by Ames as Indian Agent.
  - ALS to Mrs. H. B. Griggs, 1869 Aug. 2; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 5)
    A letter, written as Commissioner of Indian Affairs, stating that he is unable to secure a position in Washington for "Andrews, an invalid soldier."
  - ALS to N. H. Parker, 1869 Sept. 23; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 5)
    A note from New York that he hopes to be at Cattaraugus on Wednesday with Minnie "provided the trains run."
  - ALS to N. H. Parker, 1869 Oct. 4; Marshall, O. H. (Box 5)
    A letter, which accompanied a copy of an Indian petition to prohibit sale of liquor to the Six Nations, which Marshall believes "may be of interest to your Temperance Division."
  - Report, 1871 Jan. 12; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 5)
    "Report of Hon. E.S. Parker, Commissioner of Indian Affairs, to the Hon. Secretary of the Interior, on the communication of William Welsh, Esq., relative to the management of Indian Affairs." Pamphlet of five pages, published Washington, 1870 [!].
  - ALS to [U.S. Grant], 1871 June 29; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 5)
    Draft of resignation as Commissioner of Indian Affairs, to take effect Aug. 1, 1871, addressed to the President.
  - Investigation into Indian Affairs, 1871 ?; Chipman, N. P. (Box 5)
    "Investigation into Indian Affairs, before the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives. Argument of N.P. Chipman, on behalf of Hon. E.S. Parker, Commissioner of Indian Affairs." Washington, 1871. 121 p.
  - Civil War records of Seneca Indians, 1873 Nov. 3-6; Anonymous (Box 5)
    Pencilled data in leather bound notebook and on loose sheet, giving names, approximate ages, etc. of about 20 Seneca Indians, together with brief testimony concerning their participation in the War of 1812.
  - ALS to N. H. Parker, 1876 Apr. 1; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 5)
    A reply, with which Ely enclosed a letter from the Commissioner concerning the New York Agent's interpreter, and advising that he plans to take Minnie out of school in May and send her to Nic for the summer.
  - [Washington?] Newspaper, 187? Jan. 2; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 5)
    Clipping headed "The Treaty of Suffalo Creek," outlining the facts connected with the claim of the New York Indians to a balance of 31,971,295 due them by the federal government.
  - ALS to Caroline Parker Mt. Pleasant, 1884 Apr. 10; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 5)
    Note sent with some newspaper clippings, stating that Minnie is getting along nicely and "will be walking in a week or so."
  - ALS to William C. Bryant, 1884 May 8 and June 25; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 5)
    Newspaper reprint of an exchange of letters regarding the authenticity of Red Jacket's remains to be reinterred by the Buffalo Historical Society.
  - Address delivered upon reinterment of Red Jacket, 1884 [Oct. 9?]; Bryant, William C. (Box 5)
    Mutilated clipping from a Buffalo newspaper of an address delivered on the occasion of the reinterment of the remains of Red Jacket and other famous Indian chiefs, at Forest Lawn Cemetery, by the Buffalo Historical Society
  - ALS to A.H. Markland, 1885 Apr. 10; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 5)
    Note that accompanied the return of a clipping, stating "General Grant is almost gone... I get full accounts from Fred."
  - Letter to "Utica Observer", 1885 June 15; Wright, W. W. (Box 5)
    Newspaper reprint of a letter dealing with personal reminiscences of Ely S. Parker and of Ely's early estimate of Grant as "a most extraordinary man [who] will win a name and fame which has had no parallel in modern times."
  - ALS to A.H. Markland, 1885 June 18; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 5)
    A letter to one of Grant's schoolmates at Maysville, Ky., which criticizes articles by Badeau on Grant, dealing with the latter's forenames and other matters.
  - ALS to Mrs. Harriet M. Converse, 1885 July 7; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 5)
    Letter addressed to "Gayaneshaoh" with which was enclosed a list of Seneca words suitable as names for an "old man," "a rising young man," and a "promising young woman."
  - Deganawidah epic, [1885?]; [Newhouse, Seth?] (Box 5)
    According to A.C. Parker, "This manuscript is a portion of the Newhouse version of the Legend of Dekanwida and the founding of the League of the Iroquois, together with the rite of condolence." [For a photostat of a manuscript in the same hand, and a discussion of same by W. N. Fenton, see Film 345, and their Proceedings 93 (1949): 141-158.]
  - ALS to Col. [A.H. Markland?], 1886 Jan. 27; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 6)
    Letter, advising that he has "little or no recollection of the matters revived by Genl. Wallace," and that Col. Rowley is dying in Chicago.
  - Membership card, G.A.R., Reno Post, No. 44, Dept. of New York, New York City, [1886?]; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 6)
    General E. S. Parker's membership card.
  - ALS to Harriet M. Converse, 1887 Apr. 12; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 6)
    Note advising that a "horrid reptile" is being sent to her, apparently in fulfillment of a request.
  - ALS to N. H. Parker, 1888 Mar. 31; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 6)
    Brief letter stressing the necessity for unity among the Indians in pressing their Kansas claims.
  - Mountpleasant, Caroline Parker, 1888? (Box 6)
    Images note: Photograph of Caroline, sister of Ely S. Parker and wife of John Mountpleasant.
    - Caroline Parker Mountpleasant, 1888?
  - ALS to Harriet M. Converse, 1890 Mar. 8; Salisbury, J. H. (Box 6)
    Letter from a doctor stating that Ely Parker is suffering from diabetes and has been requested to call often "as a social patient, without charge."
  - AL to [Harriet M. Converse], 1890 Mar. 24; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 6)
    An acknowledgment of a letter in which Ely states "The R.J. business looks encouraging, all owing to your perseverance and courage." He concludes with references to his poor health.
  - New York World, 1891 June 29 (Box 6)
    Newspaper clipping reporting the ceremony at Oshwaken, near Syracue, during which the adoption of Mrs. Harriet M. Converse by the Seneca in April was "confirmed by the governmental authority... of all the tribes composing the Iroquois Confederacy."
  - ALS to Caroline G. Mt. Pleasant, 1891 Aug. 24; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 6)
    Power of attorney to receive "my proportionate share of all annuities."
  - ADfMs, 1891 Sept. 24; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 6)
    Draft of an address on the occasion of the unveiling of a monument dedicated by the New York Tammany Regiment to the memory of comrades killed in the Civil War. A prominent feature of the monument is a figure of the Delaware chief, Tammany.
  - "Mrs. Caroline Mt. Pleasant.", 1892 [Mar. 20] (Box 6)
    Obituary from an undated, unidentified newspaper, concerning Caroline Parker Mountpleasant who "died yesterday...aged about sixty years."
  - Buffalo Express, 1892 [Mar. 20] (Box 6)
    Typewritten copy of an incomplete newspaper obituary of "Caroline Mountpleasant, often called the `Queen of the Tuscaroras,' who died on the 19th inst."
  - ALS to Edward Poodry, 1892 Mar. 29; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 6)
    Letter concerning a power-of-attorney, authorizing his niece and her husband "to make such settlement in my name...as your good judgment may dictate" in the settlement of Caroline's estate.
  - ALS to Ely S. Parker, 1892 Apr. 9; Pound, John E. (Box 6)
    A copy in the handwriting of Ely S. Parker of a reply from the attorney for the administrators of John Mountpleasant's estats. Freeman Guide 3619.
  - ALS to [Laura Doctor], 1892 Apr. 15; 1p.; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 6)
    Letter enclosing correspondence with lawyer [Pound] and asking his niece to pay the Akron undertaker.
  - ALS to Laura M. Doctor, 1892 Aug. 9; 1p.; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 6)
    Power of attorney authorizing his niece to receive "my share of all annuities."
  - ALS to William H. Samson, 1892 Oct. 17; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 6)
    A signed typewritten reply to a request for a list of books on the Six Nations.
  - ALS to Harrlet Converse, 1894 July 10; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 6)
    A letter addressed to "my dear Snipe," and signed "The Wolf." Ely acknowledges two letters Mrs. Converse wrote to him while on a trip. He states "I do not feel well... I am very tired and care not how soon the end comes."
  - ALS to [Harriet M. Converse], 1895 Jan. 26; 1p.; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 6)
    Note addressed to "Dear Snipe" and signed "The Wolf" stating that a letter he has copied as requested is poorly written because of his ill health.
  - [New York?] Newspaper, 1895 Aug. 31?] (Box 6)
    Obituary of Ely S. Parker.
  - [New York Herald?], 1895 [Sept. 1?] (Box 6)
    Images note: Obituary of Ely S. Parker, and newspaper photograph.
  - [New York?] Tribune, 1895 Sept. 1 (Box 6)
  - [New York?] Newspaper, 1895 [Sept. 3?] (Box 6)
    Clipping concerning Ely S. Parker's funeral which "took place yesterday afternoon at 2:30 o'clock from the residence of his life long friend, Arthur S. Brown in Fairfield."
  - Obituary from Military Order of the Loyal Legion of the United States, 1895 Nov. 1; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 6)
    "In memoriam. Ely Samuel Parker, Brevet Brigadier-General, late U.S. Army, died at Fairfield, Conn., August 30th, 1895."
  - Photograph of bust of Ely S. Parker, 1895 [?]; Kelly, James (Box 6)
    Images note: 2 black and white photographs of a bust made in 1895, shortly before Parker's death. The original is in the Rochester Museum.
  - Obituary of Ely S. Parker, 1896 Nov.; Smith, J. C. (Box 6)
    Reprint in the Columbus, O. "Masonic Chronicles," of an obituary article on Ely S. Parker, that originally appeared in the "Report of the Illinois Masonic Veteran Association." Lodge memberships, with dates of affiliation, are sketched. Images note: newspaper clipping photograph.
  - [Buffalo Courier], [1896 Dec. 6] (Box 6)
    Incomplete clipping concerning Red Jacket relics offered for sale, including the medal presented to Red Jacket by Washington, and worn for many years by Ely S. Parker.
  - [Buffalo Express], 1897 Jan. 20 (Box 6)
    Newspaper notice of the reinterment of Ely S. Parker's remains by the Buffalo Historical Society in Forest Lawn Cemetery.
  - Converse, Harriet Maxwell, 1897 Jan. 24 (Box 6)
    Clipping from the Buffalo Express, relating the prophetic `broken rainbow' vision of Elizabeth Parker before the birth of her son Ely.
  - Title to the Seneca Indian Reservations, 1902 Apr. 7; Andrews, Charles T. (Box 6)
    Reprint of an article, which appeared in the New York Sun under the caption "The Title to the Seneca Indian Reservations: The Courts' Answer to Judge Davie's Argument on H.R. Bill 12,270." The author refutes the Ogden Land Co.'s claims to the Cattaraugus and Allegany Reservations by citing treaties between the U.S. and Seneca Indians, and legal decisions rendered by the Courts of New York State.
  - ALS Cy to U.S. Congress, [1902?]; John, Andrew (Box 6)
    Carbon copy of a typed petition, signed by a New York Indian, objecting to section 5 of H.R. 12,270, providing for the purchase of the Ogden Land Co.'s title to lands on the Cattaraugus, Allegany and Tuscarora Reservations.
  - ALS to Editor of the San Diego Union, [1903 Aug.?]; Cadwallader, S. (Box 6)
    Letter calling attention to inaccuracies in newspaper accounts of Ely S. Parker at the time of his death.
  - TLS Cy to E.G. Miner, 1912 Mar. 3; Samson, W. H. (Box 6)
    Typewritten copy of a letter, enclosing the list of corrections to the "League of the Iroquois" which Morgan made in his own copy and giving brief biographical facts on ALS to whom the book was dedicated.
  - Letter to Buffalo Express. Editor, [1915 Mar. 25?]; Bacheldor, Louise. (Box 6)
    Letter to the Editor of the Buffalo Express from a classmate of Ely Parker's at Yates Academy.
  - Address (extract) on the sesqui-centennial of St. Patrick's Lodge No. 4, Johnstown, 1916 Sept. 4; Ehlers, Edward M.L. (Box 6)
    Typewritten extract of an address on the occasion of the sesqui-centennial of St. Patrick's Lodge No. 4, Jamestown, suggesting similarities between Iroquois Long House and Masonic Lodge symbolism.
  - Invitation, 1922 June 2; Ely Parker Lodge No. 1002, Buffalo (Box 6)
    Invitation and program of dedication ceremonies.
  - Brief sketch of the life of Ely Parker, 1922 June 16; Price, John H. (Box 6)
    "A brief sketch of the life of Ely Parker, presented to Ely Parker Lodge No. 1002 [Buffalo] by Akron Lodge No. 527."
  - ALS to A.C. Parker, 1931 Feb. 21; Barnard, Mrs. M. H. (Box 6)
    Recollections of a former resident of Batavia "now over 90 yrs." who knew Caroline and William Parker.
  - Red Embers of the Long House, 1945?; Parker, Arthur Caswell, 1881-1955 (Box 6)
    "Red Embers of the Long House." (Three chapters of and unpublished manuscript, gleaned from letters in the Ely S. Parker Collection and other cited documents. Typewritten carbon copy.)
  - Buying Buffalo [city] from the Indians, 1946 Oct. 11; Manley, Henry S. (Box 6)
    Reprint of an address before the New York Historical Association, entitled "Buying Buffalo [city] from the Indians." The author deals with the activities of Herman B. Potter, Orlando Allen, James Stryker, Henry P. Wilcox, John F. Schermerhorn, Ransom H. Gillett, Nathaniel T. Strong and others connected with the Treaty of 1838, by means of which the Ogden Land Co. secured title to the Buffalo Creek Reservation. Bibliography.
  - [Buffalo?] Newspaper, n.d. (Box 6)
    News item concerning a Council of the Six Nations, with a description of the Feather Dance, led by Edward Cornplanter.
  - ALS to Ely S. Parker, n.d.; Childs, J. T. (Box 6)
    Letter dated May 27 from an engineer asking Ely "to send Turner to Mrs. Murray's for my large boots" which he would like to have sent on to him in Batavia.
  - The Much Admired Song of the Indian Chief [poem], Gale, Jonathan S. (Box 6)
  - The Senecas [poem]., n.d.; Hosmer, William H. C. (Box 6)
    Photostat of a [published?] poem.
  - ALS to Society of Friends, Jimerson, Samuel (Box 6)
    An account of his experiences and the havoc and discouragement brought about by continual removals resulting from treaties and land sales.
  - Morgan, Lewis Henry, n.d. (Box 6)
    Print of a portrait by Minnie R. Wyman, the original of which was presented as a gift to Union College on Nov. 28, 1945, by A.C. Parker and others.
  - Ely Parker's early life, n.d.; Napier, John H. (Box 6)
    Details of Ely Parker's early life and personality, narrated by a Rochester resident whose uncle and aunt took Ely to country dances.
  - ALS to [?] Parker, n.d.; Parker, Caroline (Box 6)
    Part of a letter to a brother telling of a quarrel resulting from N.T. Strong's failure to get Nic's office [as interpreter?].
  - [?] to Caroline Parker, n.d.; Unidentified. (Box 6)
    A copy of "Song of the Last Indian Warriors on Leaving the Valley of the Ohio," by Mrs. A.L.R. Dufour. A brief note states the sender hopes to be in "N.Y. again by the 1st of July."
  - Agreements, speeches and miscellaneous data copied from Charlevoix..., 37p.; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 6)
    Agreements, speeches and miscellaneous data copied from Charlevoix, De Witt Clinton, Cadwallader Colden, George Heriot, Thomas Pownall, John Smith and other printed sources.
  - Ancient Rites of the Condoling Council, Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 6)
    A.C. Parker states the source of this manuscript is debatable, but that it may be a copy of Horatio Hale's "The Iroquois Book of Rites."
  - ALS to the President of the U.S., n.d. (Box 6)
    Draft, part of which is missing, recommending O. Turner for a position as Indian Agent in the "states or territories."
  - Notes on mythology, n.d.; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 6)
    Five pages of pencilled notes and poetry concerning dwarfs, elves, fairies, nymphs and references to classical mythology.
  - AMs fragment, History of the Government, Manners, Customs..., n.d.; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 6)
  - AMs Address, n.d.; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 6)
    Part of an address delivered on the anniversary of a Grand Lodge, dealing with the failure of some members to live up to the high ideals of Masonry. Pages 5-7 are missing.
  - Errors in the League of the Iroquois, n.d.; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 6)
    Single page of "errors" concerning the League of the Iroquois, which apparently refer to suggested corrections of a manuscript.
  - Essays, n.d.; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 6)
    Three essays on the following subjects: discontentment, education, and the passing of the need for Indian guides.
  - Essays on the Iroquois, n.d.; Parker, Ely Samuel, 1828-1895 (Box 6)
    Three undated, unsigned essays on the organization of the Iroquois and their religious beliefs.
  - Parker, William, n.d. (Box 6)
    Images note: Mounted photograph from a daguerreotype of Ely Parker's father. Freeman guide, 3610
    - William Parker, n.d.
  - Remarks on Christianity, n.d.; 3p. AMs; Two Guns, Henry (Box 6)
    Transcript of remarks on Christianity delivered before a group of Church members on the Reservation.
  - Sermons (outlines), n.d.; 17p.; Wright, Asher (Box 6)
    Outlines in English for sermons.
  - Sermons (outline), n.d.; 3p.; Wright, Asher (Box 6)
    Three scraps of paper with notes concerning Joe Snow's sister's will, Henrietta Bennett's schooling, and other reservation Indians.
- Series II. Linguistic Material, n.d.; 0.25 linear feet (Box 7)
  - Bible. O.T. [?] Chapters [38]-47. (Box 7)
    Translation into Seneca of unidentified portions. 35 pages, 7-1/2 Ö 12-1/2 inches.
  - Bible. O.T. Psalms (Box 7)
    Translations into Seneca of the Psalm of David and Psalms 39, 103 and 139.
  - Bible. N.T. Acts. Chapters I-[IV], IX-XIX, 33p. (Box 7)
    Translated into Seneca.
  - Bible. N.T. Epistle of Paul to the Ephesians (Box 7)
  - Bible. N.T. Matthew 25-40. (Box 7)
  - Bible. N.T. James. (Box 7)
    Chapter IV, Verses 1-10, translated into Seneca.
    "Danehhodih nayuhdaok..." Seneca text, without English translation, unidentified as to author and subject matter. 5-1/2 pages, 7-3/4 Ö 13 inches.
    "Daonanekuh nedewadoh..." Seneca text, without English translation, unidentified as to author and subject matter. 18-1/2 pages, 7-3/4 Ö 13 inches.
    Hymns translated into Seneca. 6 p. in mss., 1 printed.
    Seneca texts, without English, in various handwritings, unidentified as to subject matter. 16 sheets of assorted sizes, some double.
    Seneca word lists, without English definitions, in various handwritings, on 6 sheets of paper of assorted sizes.